## RYAN LANDMAN

For the past 12 years I've worked both in-house and within an agency environment developing responsive websites and web applications for all types of clients. My focus is in front-end development (though I do have expericence with back-end development, primarily PHP and Wordpress). I've found that my background in graphic design has helped me collaborate effectively with designers to bridge the gap between creative and development.



P: 610-585-4590
E: ryan.landman@gmail.com
W: landman.dev

## EXPERIENCE

April 2019 - May 2020

1600VER90

**Senior Front End Developer / Interim Tech Lead** 

In addition to my previous responsibilities at 160over90, I was also tasked with leading client conversations around technology/recommending solutions, mentoring Junior Developers, and improving the efficiency of the development process. During this time I worked closely with Producers to implement a process for accurately scoping development effort while eliminating scope creep throughout the UX/Design phases. I also developed a framework for rapidly building landing pages using a collection of components common to all historical projects.

April 2018 - April 2019

1600VER90

**Front End Developer** 

Developed client websites for both higher education and consumer clients with an emphasis on web accessibility best practices and WCAG 2.1 compliance. I worked closely with the Design team to translate atomic design systems into scalable and mainatainable component libraries, leveraging Vue.js for all interactivity. Clients included: Blue Origin, The Philadelphia Zoo, LSU, Jefferson University, University of Pennsylvania, and Rowan University.

June 2017 - April 2018

QUATTRO

**Senior Web Developer** 

Responsible for front and back-end development of all internal and client web sites (Wordpress and static), as well as landing pages and emails with Hubspot integration. I also managed and mentored a Junior Developer/QA Analyst.

March 2015 - June 2017

DMW DIRECT

**Front End Developer** 

Responsible for front and back-end development of all internal and client web sites.

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF THE ARTS

**BFA Graphic Design, 2008** 

Philadelphia, PA

SKILLS

HTML

CSS

JavaScript

Vue.js

PHP

Twig

Web Accessibility

Wordpress

Photoshop

Illustrator

Sketch

Project Management